# **Anas Al-Sammarraie**

# **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

anas599@yahoo.com | +962-7 9285 6973 | My Github | Linkedin | Twitter | My portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

Junior-level Full-Stack Developer boasting experience in both IT and development. Known for exceptional collaboration and communication skills, and capable of designing and implementing scalable software solutions. Proficiency demonstrated in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React JS, Ruby on Rails, and PostgreSQL.

# **SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, Reactjs, Nextjs, Redux, jQuery, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap

Back-End: Ruby on Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, AWS cloud computing, RSpec, TDD, Linux, Agile, Waterfall

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, collaboration, and communicating

# **EXPERIENCE**

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

#### **Full Stack Web Developer**

November 2022 - Present

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building multiple full-stack projects independently and via pair programming.

<u>Crypto Bloa</u> — A Next.js web app with a Prisma adapter for real-time cryptocurrency data. Engage in community-driven discussions, and vote on comments. NextAuth ensures secure authentication.

Built with: Nextjs, NextAuth, Redux, API, PSQL, Tailwind,

<u>Tutoring App</u> — The tutoring App enables users to manage classes, It also provides reservation functionality, allowing users to make reservations and view their reservation details,

Built with: Reactjs, Redux, API, Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap, PSQL

Budget-App — A Ruby on Rails app for managing personal finances with pSQL and Bootstrap, built for iOS/Android to Track your expenses, set budget goals, and gain insights into your spending habits.

Built with: Ruby on Rails, API, PSQL, Bootstrap, CSS

**MICROVERSE** Remote

#### Mentor (Volunteer)

January 2023 - March 2023

- Mentored 3 Junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and performance by 20%.
- Provided advice and tips to 10+ students on how to maintain motivation and longevity.

Al-Khora LLC. Amman, Jordan July 2017 - 2023

#### IT support engineer

- Provided prompt and effective support, ensuring minimal downtime and smooth operations.
- Actively contributed to Continuous Improvement initiatives within the IT department,
- Achieved a 99.2% success rate in independently resolving Level 2 tech support tickets.

#### **EDUCATION**

**MICROVERSE** December 2022 - June 2023

### Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers

Baghdad COES University Bachelor's degree in Computer Software Engineering October 2012 - April 2017